BENARD ARIHO

Position: HSE OFFICER/SUPERVISOR/COORDINATOR

SUMMARY.

BBA GRADUATE & NEBOSH HOLDER WITH 8+ YEARS EXPERIENCE IN- CIVIL WORKS-ROADS & BRIDGES,INFRASTRUCTURE,PILING/FOUNDATIONS,OIL&GAS,ONSHORE & OFFSHORE/MARINE, BUILDINGS, MANUFACTURING, TRANSPORTATION,FACILITIES AND GENERAL CONSTRUCTION.

Mobile & Whatsapp: +971 558473002

Current Location: DUBAI-UAE

Email: benardariho@gmail.com



I am a diligent, successful and experienced occupational health, safety, environment officer (HSEO), hardworking who consistently monitors and manages work sites and processes to ensure proper compliance with versatile and highly effective at working independently and as part of a team.

A professional having a vast and vigorous experience in undertaking a variety of sensitive and complex project assignments and accomplishing them while achieving distinguished results.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCES AND SKILLS

- > Microsoft office, result driven, prioritizing and time management.
- Organizational skills, analytical, problem solving and good communication
- Management system standards- ISO: 45001:2018, ISO:14001:2015, 14001:2015
- Risk assessment and method statement, HSE policy implementation
- HSE planning and management, work site inspections, site safety management
- ➤ HSE report writing, reporting and HSE documentation
- Internal and external audits
- > Training and development (scheduled & non-scheduled).

WORK EXPERIENCE:

FEB. 2023 TO DATE. (DUBAI- UAE)

EMPLOYER: GEOMAR GULF LLC- AL SHAFAR GROUP

JOB TITTLE: HSE SUPERVISOR

1)Project: ADQ-EWEC 5.2 GW solar project Abu Dhabi UAE (On going)

Client: Power china-Abu Dhabi

Scope: Installation of H-steel profile beams/piles and testing

2)Project: Al Maryah Grand Steps, Abu Dhabi –Uae Contractor: Gulf Contracting And Land Scaping (GCL)

Scope Of Work- Construction Works Of a pontoon System With 4 Piles-Installation Of

marine Steel Tabular Piles)



3)Project: Onshore(Abutments) And Offshore Piling- Safwa-Rahima Marine Sea Bridge

(Kingdom Of Saudi Arabia)

Contractor: Shade Corporation Ltd-Ksa

Consultant: Euro Group-Ksa

Client: Ministry Of Transport- Ksa

4) Project: Dubai Canal- Jb 11 & Jb 12 Canal Side Private Pontoon- Alsafa Dubai- Uae.

Scope: Installation of marine piles

5) Project: Construction Of New Bridge At Abu Al Abyad Island Abu Dhabi-Uae.

Client: The Private Department Of The President Of Uae Contractor: National Marine Dredging Company (Nmdc)

Scope: Onshore & Offshore Piling

DEC. 2021 to JAN. 2023. (DUBAI-UAE)

EMPLOYER: GTGC-TECHNICAL SERVICES LLC.

JOB TITTLE: HSE OFFICER

1)Project: Kifaf Development Phase 2- Twin Tower 43- Level High Rise (Dubai-UAE

Client: Ssang Yong Engineering And Construction Co. Ltd

Consultant: Atkins

Scope: Ceiling Protective Coatings, Decorative Painting And Gypsum Works

2) Project: Abrasive Blasting And Protective Coating/Painting Of Petro Chemical Storage Tanks (Internal &External) And Associated Facilities At Jafza Dubai-Uae.

Contractor: Gantoot General Mechanical Engineering (Ggme).

Client: Aquachemie Middle East.

3)Project: Surface Preparation/Abrasive Blasting And Coating Of Tank 404,302 Internal Storage And IFR, New Logo Supply, 22mtr Height- Four Tower Fixed Scaffold Erection And Dismantling, Installation And External Tank Washing By Rope Access On The 6 Tanks And One Substation At Jafza Dubai- Uae (Star Energy Oil Tanking To Star Energy Advario)

Client: Star Energy Advario- Jafza Dubai-Uae

4)Project: (Shut Down) Hydro And Abrasive Blasting, Protective Coating And Painting Of Natural Gas Pipelines And Associated Facilities At L-2, L-1 Stations & Two Ng-Skid At E-Station Dubai-Uae.

Client: Dubai Electricity And Water Authority (Dewa) Main Generation Power Station (Japs) At Jabel Ali Dubai-Uae

JULY, 2019 To AUGUST 2021 (Uganda)

Employer: East Africa Concrete Products Ltd

Job Title: HSE Officer

Scope Of Work: Manufacturing Of Electric Concrete Poles, Stay Blocks & Other Concrete Products, Installation/Erection Of Poles, Transportation And Electrical Lines Maintenance Works

NOV. 2015 To DEC. 2018 (Qatar)

Employer: Leighton Contracting Qatar (WLL)

Job Title: HSE Inspector

1)Project: New Orbital Highway And Truck Route (Noh3) And Infrastructure Developments On Qatar Petroleum Live Underground & On Ground Oil And Gas Lines And Future Pipe On Ground Tunnel Erection.

Main Contractor: Leighton Contracting & Aljaber Engineering (Jv)

Consultant: Aecom Middle East

Client: Ashghal- Government Of Qatar- Public Works Authority & Qatar Petroleum

2)Project: Construction Of Two Pipelines For Two Sections At Doha Mega Reservoir Corridor (Trench Excavation, Supply, Installation, Testing And Commissioning Of 120km-1600mm Diameter Ductile Iron Pipes And Fittings.

Client: Kahramma-Qatar Electricity & Water Authority

GENERAL RESPONSIBILITIES

- Coordinate and monitor all health, safety and environmental activities to ensure agreed safety and loss prevention standards are fully implemented and properly followed,
- > Provide information, advice and support to all levels of project staff regarding health, safety and environment practices, legislations and procedures.
- ➤ Establishing HSE committees and ensure meetings are conducted and ensuring members play their roles to achieve set goals and continuous improvement
- Constant and continuous site inspections and ensure remedial action is taken on any non-compliance.
- > promote safety culture with in the work place by ensuring all levels of employees are aware and understand their responsibilities with regard to HSE issues,
- ➤ Conducting trainings and TBT in accordance with hazards identified and new tasks at site and ensuring training program is followed.
- ➤ Conduct risk assessments and JSA's for new tasks and review subcontractor submitted documents for any recommendation if any.
- ➤ Monitoring of environmental impacts on marine (water and ecology) discharges to marine, flora and fauna.
- Liaise and coordinate for internal and external audits and ensure NC's are followed up for corrective actions.
- > Exercise mock drills to verify the effectiveness of emergency response procedures and resources.

EDUCATION/PROFESSIONAL DETAILS.

	COURSE NAME	YEAR OF COMPLETION	INSTITUTION	COUNTRY/LOCATION
1	BACHELOR OF BUSINESS	OCT. 2011	BISHOP STUART UNIVERSITY	UGANDA
	ADMINISTRATION		MBARARA UGANDA	
PR0F	ESSIONAL COURSES			
1	NEBOSH IGC 1,2&3	FEB. 2017	DOHA INDUSTRIAL SAFETY SERVICES	QATAR
2	IOSH MANAGING SAFELY	FEB. 2017	DOHA INDUSTRIAL SAFETY SERVICES	QATAR
3	GENERAL HEALTH,SAFETY AND ENVIRONMENTAL AWARENESS	MAY. 2018	BRITISH SAFETY COUNCIL	QATAR

OTHER HSE CERTIFICATIONS/TRAININGS

authorized gas testing, coshh certification,ISO 45001:2018(CPD),ISO 9001:2015(bureau veritas),HABC fire safety ,basic first aid and cpr,H2S& BA,Lifting supervisor,basic rigging and slinging

All certificates available upon request.

Other Info.

Marital Status: Married Religion: Christian Nationality: Ugandan Passport no. B1197100 Date of birth: 02/06/1989

Visa type: employment visa with NOC

Languages: English (fluent)

Hindi (working knowledge)